RG 074:017, Estelle Benham Genealogical Papers
Connecticut State Library
Estelle Benham genealogical papers
1888-1927
Connecticut State Library
Benham, Estelle
.5 cubic feet
Correspondence and genealogy notes on the Benham Family.
RG074_017
1933-002
Biographical Note
Mary Estelle Benham was born in Hampton, Conn. on August 20, 1852 to Nelson and Fidelia (Bulkeley) Higgins. Her family moved to New Britain when she was four years old and she lived there most of her life. She married Frederic W. Benham. She was a member of the Connecticut Society of Daughters of Founders and Patriots of America, the Connecticut Society of Mayflower Descendants, the Women’s Club of New Britain, Historical Society of Hartford, and Esther Stanley Chapter, DAR. Mrs. Benham died on October 30, 1953.
Scope and Contents
Series 1. Correspondence, includes letters containing genealogy data. Included are letters from Elbridge H. Benham of Kansas City, Missouri, who was compiling a Benham genealogy. Series 2. Genealogy notes contain notes gathered from various sources. There is a bound manuscript volume of the Benham Family Record rewritten in 1904.
Related Material
Benham family: History and Genealogy Unit Special Genealogical File, 1853-1969
Index Terms
Persons:
Benham, Estelle
Family Names:
Benham family
Places:
Connecticut -- Genealogy
Document Types:
Correspondence; Genealogies
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
Donated by Estelle Benham on May 8, 1933.
Container List
- Series 1. Correspondence, 1888-1927, undated
  - Baird, E. G., undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Benham, Elbridge H. (Box 1)
    - 1901-1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1906-1908 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1912, 1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Also genealogy notes.
    - Elbridge H. Benham to M. L. Whitman, 1902-1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Benham, N. L., 1896-1901 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brown, E. R., 1904-1908 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cooke, H. Ruth, 1897, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ferry, Charles B., 1888, 1894-1896 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Knous, Mary A., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1876-1927, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series 2. Genealogy Notes, 1904, undated
  - General, undated (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - New Haven probate records, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - First Church in New Haven, 1639 to 1806, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - New Haven town records, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Boutecon genealogy, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Genealogy chart of Edward Monroe Benham, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Benham records, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Benham family record, rewritten 1904; 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 17)